連れてけ 早く!!
でも！
(新八)からくりが涙を!?
いったい どうなって!?
(銀時)お前!?
うわ～！
銀さん！
新八！ 飛べ！
(ﾒｲﾄﾞ)渡すんですの 私たちに！
新八 源外のじいさんのとこへ➡
後から行くから！ 早く行け!!
ｼﾞｬﾏは やめるんですの！
♪♪～
You're...
A robot shedding tears... How is that possible?!
Hand it over! To us!
Stop...
interfering!
Gin-san!
Shinpachi! Jump!
Shinpachi!
Take her to old man Gengai's place! Hurry!
But!
I'll join you later!
Get going!
[Tama-san, A.K.A. Fuyo No. i-Zero contained data known as "The Seed" concealed inside her.]
[Can Gintoki and his friends protect Tama-san?! And what is the true objective of the Fuyo Project?!]
["Too Many Cuties Can Make You Sick"]
うお～!!
♪♪～
定春！
Sadaharu!
♪♪～
逃がすんじゃないですの！
Don't let them get away! Cleanse--!
お掃除 する… ﾎﾟｫ!!
ｵ ﾎﾟｫｼﾞ…｡
(神楽)しつこいね ﾄﾝﾎﾞ目玉｡
You don't give up, do you, bug-eyes?
(ﾒｲﾄﾞたち)わ～!!
(ﾒｲﾄﾞたち)わ～！
神楽～！ 早く乗れ!!
Kagura! Jump on, hurry!
銀ちゃん！
Gin-chan!
ｸｿｯ いったい
どうなってるんだ？
Crap. What the heck is going on?! Why is this happening to me...?
なんで こんな目に…｡
あっちも こっちも➡
Over there...
Over here...
どっちも
ﾒｲﾄﾞだらけじゃないかぁ!!
Nothing but maids everywhere!
(芙蓉)敵の狙いは 私です｡
The enemy is after me.
どうやら あなたは流れとはいえ➡
It seems that in the course of things, you ended up with the most dangerous mission.
最も危険な任務に
ついてしまったようです｡
(芙蓉)私の計算からいくと…｡
By my calculations...
あなたの生存確率は
残念ながら ５％以下です｡
Your chances of survival are unfortunately below 5 percent.
ｲﾔな計算たたき出すの
やめてくんない!?
Mind not coming up with such depressing calculations?!
(芙蓉)ですが 私を捨てて
あなただけ逃げれば➡
However, if you abandon me and run your chances jump to 25 percent.
これが 25％まで
はねあがります｡
…卵さん｡
Tama-san, your calculations apply to ordinary people. Samurai are different.
それは 普通の人間の
勘定の仕方です｡
侍は 違う｡
侍？
Samurai?
例え あなたを見捨て
25％の確率で➡
Even if he had a 25 percent chance of surviving by abandoning you, a samurai would still die.
運よく助かったとしても
侍は 死ぬんです｡
護るべきものを 護れずに
生き残っても➡
If he survives but couldn't protect what was important to him,
a samurai might as well be dead.
侍は 死んだと同じなんです｡
Even if I have only a 5 percent chance of surviving,
５％しか
生き残る確率がないなら➡
その５％を使って
あなたを護る｡
I will use that 5 percent to save you.
いったん 護ると決めたものは
何が何でも護りとおす！
Once a samurai decides to protect something, he protects it to the very end!
それが 侍だぁ～！
That's what a samurai is!
出自も 不明確｡
まして殺人の容疑が➡
You would protect someone of unknown origin who is also suspected of murder?
かかった者を護る…｡
侍… 理解しかねます｡
Samurai... It does not compute. There is nothing in my data about it.
私のﾃﾞｰﾀには
該当するものがありません｡
Then...please add it to your data
じゃあ ﾃﾞｰﾀに
付け加えておいてください｡
勇者よりも 魔王よりも
上のところに！
above both the Hero and the Demon King!
[Note: Hero and Demon King are Dragon Quest characters.]
ついでに
女の子の涙に弱いってね！
And add that they can't stand the sight of a woman's tears!
了解しました… 魔王より上➡
Understood.
I will add it above the Demon King, together with the Great Demon's subordinates.
大魔王の配下のところに
付け加えておきます｡
日本語って難しい～!!
Such a convoluted hierarchy!
…見えてきた！
I can see it!
(伍丸弐號)
目標補足 邪魔者は排除し➡
Target acquired.
We will eliminate the nuisance and proceed to recover model No. i-Zero.
零號機回収にうつります｡
うわ～!!
うお～！
離すね！ どこまで
ついてくるつもりｱﾙか!?
Let go!! How far are you going to tag along?! Darn it! Darn it!
このっ このっ!!
(ﾒｲﾄﾞ)逃がしませんの｡
I'm not letting you get away.
邪魔者は お掃除ですの｡
Troublemakers must be cleansed.
ｳｷﾞｬｰ!! ﾎﾗｰｱﾙ!!
It's like a horror movie!
どけ～！ 神楽～!!
Stay clear, Kagura!
やったか？
Did that do it?
首なしで!!
Without a head...?!
(ﾒｲﾄﾞたち)わ～！
いかん！
This is bad!
定春！
Sadaharu!
(ﾒｲﾄﾞ)臭気確認 臭気確認｡
第一級不浄物です｡
Odor detected! Odor detected!
Level one filth. Dispose of immediately.
すみやかに 排除して下さい｡
Switching to...
(ﾒｲﾄﾞ)お掃除ﾓｰﾄﾞに移行します｡
ｺﾞﾐ掃除ですの～！
clean up mode.
Cleaning up the mess!
(ﾒｲﾄﾞたち)ｺﾞﾐ掃除ですの～！
でかした 定春！
Good job, Sadaharu!
(伍丸弐號)敵 こちらの包囲網を
突破しました｡
The enemy has broken through... our assault line.
戦闘用に改造を施された
あれだけの数の からくりを➡
I did not expect them to break through such a large number of our battle-modified robots.
突破するとは｡
人間のｽﾍﾟｯｸを➡
They have greatly exceeded human specifications.
大きく超えています｡
あの生き物は なんですか？
What kind of enemy are they? I have nothing in my database that is applicable to them.
私のﾃﾞｰﾀには
該当するものがありません｡
(目黒)侍だ｡
時代に取り残された➡
Samurai. Remnants from a relic that have been left behind by the times.
前時代の遺物｡
ﾃﾞｰﾀに加える必要はない｡
There is no need to add them to your database. They will soon be extinct.
いずれ この世から
消えゆく存在だ｡
(伍丸弐號)了解しました｡ 一応
追って 始末しておきますか？
Understood.
Shall I track them down and dispose of them?
(目黒)構わん ｱﾚは取り戻した｡
引きあげるぞ｡
Never mind. We've recovered it. Let's withdraw.
(伍丸弐號)
後始末は？ これだけの騒ぎ➡
What about clean up?
After creating such a large disturbance, the Fuyo Project may be aborted.
芙蓉ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄが 頓挫しかねません｡
Since Dr. Hayashi was murdered by a robot he created, this project will end anyway.
(目黒)林博士が
自ら創り出した からくりに➡
殺されたとあっては
どのみち このﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄは終わる｡
(目黒)そして
何もなくなった更地に➡
And from the nothingness that remains,
私の御名において➡
I will establish a true Fuyo Project under my name.
真の芙蓉ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄは
樹立されるのだ｡
Do not worry, No. To-502
案ずるな 戸ｰ伍丸弐號｡
お前には 私とともにいてもらう｡
You will remain with me.
おそらく あれを
受け入れられるのは➡
In all likelihood, you being the last robot created by Dr. Hayashi are the only one who can accept "it."
林博士が最後に創りだした
お前しかおるまい｡
零號には あれは使いこなせん｡
そして 林博士にも…｡
i-Zero cannot handle it. And nor could Dr. Hayashi...
(目黒)種子は 我々が
有効に使わせてもらう｡
We will put "The Seed"... to good use.
(ﾓﾆﾀｰを叩く音)
I told you, I don't know.
(源外)だから
知らんと言ってんだろ｡
(源外)今日は 新八どころか
一人も 客なんぞ来とらんよ｡
No one came here today, not Shinpachi, or anyone.
それにしても ﾃﾒｴら
ｴﾗｲもん 拾ってきたもんだな｡
But I'll say, you people picked up quite a troublesome thing.
まさか 人を殺めた
からくりだったなんざぁ…｡
Imagine, a robot that killed a man?
(源外)ﾃﾚﾋﾞも その話でもちきりよ｡
It's all over the TV.
…とっ捕まったってよ｡
銀ちゃん！
They're reporting it was captured.
Gin-chan!
まぁ あの首は
当然 処分されるだろうがよ｡
That head will, of course, probably be disposed of.
からくり家政婦そのもの
全部 回収して➡
Seems they've decided on a policy of recalling every robot maid and terminating them.
処分する方針に
決まったそうだぜ｡
My colleagues and I had no idea...
(目黒)ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄの
最高責任者だった 林博士が➡
if Dr. Hayashi, the leader of the project, knew beforehand that these robots would revolt.
こういった からくりの暴走を
予期していたかどうかは➡
我々の知るところではありません｡
ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄは ほぼ
博士の独断で動いていました｡
The project was carried on for the most part at Dr. Hayashi's arbitrary discretion.
責任は 全部 死んだ野郎に
押しつけて➡
We were involved only in the very periphery of the project.
They're shoving all the blame on the guy who died...
They're hiding something.
ｺｲﾂら… 何か 隠してやがらぁ…｡
泣いてやがったよ…｡
うん？
She cried...
からくりが
ぼろぼろ 涙こぼしてやがった｡
Tears trickled down that robot's cheeks.
死んだ博士に対する
懺悔の涙なのか➡
Though I don't know if they were tears of regret or sorrow at losing Dr. Hayashi.
惜別の涙なのか
知りゃしねえが…｡
そうか…｡ 流山の野郎➡
I see.
That Ryuzan was still trying to create something like that.
まだ そんなもん
創ってやがったのか｡
じいさん ｱﾝﾀ…｡
Old man, you...?
(神楽)何ｱﾙか？ それ｡
What is it?
(源外)野郎とは 昔から
ｿﾘが合わなくてなぁ｡
He and I never got along back then.
ｵﾚのからくりは 見たとおり
野暮ったいもんだが➡
As you can see, my robots are unsophisticated,
but his creations looked like living women.
野郎のそれは まるで
生きた女のようだった｡
技術の大半を 頭脳部分にあて➡
He placed most of his technology in the processing unit
and sought to make his units as close to human as possible.
いかに 人間に近づけるかを
追求したものだった｡
からくりに 心を宿す…
ﾔﾂは 人間を創りたかったのよ｡
He sought to put a soul into robots. He wanted to create humans.
実際 人間ってやつは
見方によっちゃ➡
One way to view humans is as well-engineered robots.
よくできた からくりよ｡
Especially with regard to feelings and heart, humans are mechanical works of art.
特に 感情… 心ってやつは
芸術品とも呼べる からくり｡
ｺｲﾂを 自分の手で創れたら
そりゃあ 職人冥利に尽きらぁ｡
He felt the ultimate goal of his craft would be to build such robots with his own hands.
くだらねえ｡ 人間が創りてぇなら
嫁さん つくって➡
That's poppycock.
If he wants to make humans, he should've just gotten a wife and shook his hips.
毎晩 腰振ってりゃいいだろ｡
(源外)ｶﾞﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
True!
ちげぇねえや！ だが 世の中
ｵﾚや ｵﾒｴのように➡
But the world isn't full of practical people like you and me.
乾いた連中ばっかりじゃねえや｡
野郎が変わったのは
ﾔﾂの一人娘が死んだときからだ｡
It was when his only daughter died that he began to change.
実験中のことだったらしい｡
Apparently, it happened during an experiment.
He came up with the idea of converting human personality into data and copying it into a robot.
野郎は 人間の人格をﾃﾞｰﾀ化し
からくりに ｺﾋﾟｰする技術を考えた｡
その実験体として選んだのが
こともあろうに 自分の娘だった｡
For his test subject, he chose, of all people, his own daughter.
もともとが
病弱な娘だったらしい｡
She was always a sickly girl.
There was no way she could withstand the experiment.
実験に
耐えられるはずもなかった｡
その死んだ娘の名… それが 芙蓉｡
His daughter died. Her name was Fuyo.
わかるか？ つまり 芙蓉ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄの
野郎の真の目的は…｡
Do you understand the true objective...Hayashi's true intentions for the Fuyo Project?
(源外)死んだ芙蓉を
よみがえらせること｡
He planned to bring his dead daughter, Fuyo, back to life.
(源外)ｵﾒｴたちが拾ってきた
零號機には➡
Model No. i-Zero that you picked up contained data known as "The Seed."
種子と呼ばれる ﾃﾞｰﾀが積んである｡
芙蓉を 花開かせる種子…➡
It was the seed to make Fuyo blossom. In other words, it was Fuyo's character data.
つまり
流山の娘… 芙蓉の人格ﾃﾞｰﾀだ｡
じいさん
ｱﾝﾀ なんで そんなことまで…｡
Old man, how do you know all this?
(源外)死んだ娘の人格ﾃﾞｰﾀを
引き継ぐ からくりを開発する｡
To develop a robot that could carry on his dead daughter's character data-
それが 真の芙蓉ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄの意味｡
that was the true purpose of the Fuyo Project.
だが こいつは
人間が 人間を創りだす➡
But it was man creating man; forbidden technology that stepped over the boundaries of God.
神の領域に踏み込んだ
禁断の技術｡
It didn't take long for the hyenas to gather round.
ﾊｲｴﾅが たかるのに
時間はいらねえや｡
あ！ これは…｡
This is...!
Could this be video of when the doctor was murdered?
まさか 博士が殺されたときの…!?
ｺｲﾂが!?
Did he...?!
(目黒)まったく くだらん
夢物語に つきあわされたものだ｡
Utterly ridiculous.
He has us tagging along on his dream.
But if this technology is perfected, man can create man...
だが この技術が完成すれば
人間によって 人間が…｡
いや からくりの体と
人間の感情を持った➡
Rather, we'll be able create a new kind of human, one with the body of a robot and the emotions of a human being!
新人類が創りだせる！
私は 新しき生物を創りあげた
神に等しい存在になれるのだ｡
I can become the creator of a new life form...
And equal to God.
林博士も あの世で
歯噛みしていよう｡
Dr. Hayashi must be rolling in his grave, eh, No. To-502?
なぁ 伍丸弐號… うっ！
零號機!?
ｷｻﾏ なぜ こんなところに!?
No. i-Zero?!
What're you doing here?!
ﾁｯ！ 誰か～！
零號機が暴走しているぞ！
Tsk...
Somebody! No. i-Zero has gone berserk!
(目黒)誰か～！
Somebody!
濡れ衣きせやがった…！
He framed her...
♪♪～
(流山)何を… している…
芙蓉 早く逃げるのだ… 芙蓉！
What...are...you...waiting...for, Fuyo...? Get away quickly.
Fuyo.
(流山)迎えにいく… うっ…
必ず… だから…｡
I will come for you...
For sure...so...
今は逃げろ｡
Get away for now.
流山は まだ 生きている｡
Ryuzan is still alive.
うぅ… 伍丸弐號 ｷｻﾏ…｡
No. To-502...damn you...
(目黒)からくりが 自らの意志で
創造主に逆らうなど…｡
A robot must never disobey the will of its creator...
まさか ｷｻﾏは…！
Could it be...
...you...?!
Ryuzan Hayashi is alive...
(源外)林 流山は生きている｡
伍丸弐號の中に…｡
Inside No. To-502...
流山が からくりに…？
どういうこった!?
Ryuzan...inside the robot? What do you mean?
それに なんで
ｱﾝﾀが こんなもの 持ってる？
And why do you have this thing?
I just heard it from this young lady a minute ago.
な～に… ｵﾚも 今しがた
この嬢ちゃんに聞いたところよ｡
た… 卵！ なんで お前…｡
Ta-Tama! How did you?!
やられましたね… 私が
零號機の頭部を回収する前に➡
You bested me.
Before I was able to retrieve No. i-Zero's head.
本体から 中枢電脳幹を抜き取り
仲間のもとへ…｡
You removed the central processor and passed it on to your friends.
In other words, this is an empty shell.
(伍丸弐號)つまり これは 抜け殻｡
Once a samurai makes up his mind to protect something,
侍は いったん 護ると
決めたものは 死んでも護る！
he protects it to the death.
新八が…｡
Shinpachi...
The central processor was lying outside my shop.
(源外)店の前に
中枢電脳幹が転がっておった｡
He probably threw it there before he was captured.
おそらく 捕まる前に
投げ込んだんだろ｡
新八…｡
Shinpachi...
(芙蓉)新八様のおかげで
私のﾃﾞｰﾀは護られました｡
Thanks to Shinpachi-sama, my data was protected.
And thanks to Gengai-sama, I was even able to recover the memories I had lost.
そして 源外様のおかげで
失われていた記憶も➡
回復することができました｡
種子とやらは…｡
What about "The Seed"...
The character data of the doctor's daughter, Fuyo-sama, are in here.
(芙蓉)博士の娘 芙蓉様の
人格ﾃﾞｰﾀは➡
こちらに入っております｡
Tama, what was that I saw?
おい 卵… ありゃ なんだ？
厳密にいえば 林博士は
すでに死んでいます｡
Strictly speaking, Dr. Hayashi was already dead.
林博士は 自分をも
実験体に使っていたんです｡
Dr. Hayashi used himself in his experiments.
(芙蓉)あれは 過酷な実験で
命を落とすことと引き換えに➡
That robot was the one the doctor incorporated his character data into.
But the severe experiments cost him his life.
博士の人格ﾃﾞｰﾀを組み込んだ
からくり｡
もっとも 人間に近い からくり
戸ｰ伍丸弐號｡
It's the closest human-like robot. No. To-502.
So he transferred his soul...
魂を からくりに移し変えた…｡
芙蓉ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄは
すでに成功していたというのか｡
The Fuyo Project was already a success.
(芙蓉)いいえ 初期段階では
博士の人格ﾃﾞｰﾀと同調を見せた➡
No...
At first, No. To-502 appeared in sync with the doctor's character data,
伍丸弐號も しだいに拒絶反応を
起こし始め 人格は崩壊｡
but he gradually began rejecting them until the personality was destroyed.
The doctor has changed into something else.
博士は もう
別のものへと変貌しました｡
It was all a part of his plan.
すべては彼の計画です｡
(芙蓉)ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄを手に入れたと
思わせて➡
He let deputy director Meguro think he had taken over the project...
目黒副主任を泳がせていたのは➡
to gather all the robot maids throughout Edo in one location
生みの親を殺すという問題を
起こした からくり家政婦を➡
under the pretense of recalling them for the defect of killing their creator.
強制回収処分という名目で➡
江戸中から
１か所に集めるのが 目的｡
Have you seen the deputy director?
(研究員)おい 副主任
見かけなかったか？
I haven't seen him since the press conference...
会見のあとから見かけんのだが…｡
Huh?
ん!? おい！ どうした？
Hey, what's the matter?
(研究員)それが
からくりが 命令を…｡
The robots aren't obeying their orders.
なに!? 何をやっている？
早く 前へ出んか ｷｻﾏら！
What?
What's the matter with you? Move forward, you.
(研究員)おい！
我々の命令が聞けぬの…｡
Hey, didn't you hear your orders?
命令を拒否します｡
(研究員)うわ～っ！
We refuse to comply.
I am sorry, but we have received orders that supercede yours.
(ﾒｲﾄﾞ)申し訳ありませんが
あなたたちの命令より➡
優先させる命令が下りました｡
やれ｡
(研究員たち)うわ～っ!!
Do it.
お前は…
いったい 何をするつもりだ!?
What are you planning to do?
からくり家政婦 集めて
ﾒｲﾄﾞ喫茶でも開こうってのか？
Are you gathering all the robot maids to open maid-fetish coffee shops?
芙蓉が寂しがるだろう？
Fuyo would be sad.
(芙蓉)林博士が 人間のような
からくりを創り始めたのは➡
Dr. Hayashi began creating human-like robots...
for Fuyo-sama, who lost her mother at a tender age and was lonely.
幼い頃 母を亡くし
孤独だった芙蓉様のためでした｡
病弱で
こもりがちだった 芙蓉様に➡
He wanted to create someone Fuyo,
who was frail and tended to keep to her self, could talk to...
寂しい思いをさせまい と
話し相手を…｡
始まりは ただのおもちゃでした｡
It started with mere toys...
芙蓉… お前に もう
寂しい思いはさせない｡
Fuyo, I won't let you feel lonely anymore.
(伍丸弐號)お前は
もう１人じゃない｡
You're no longer alone. You have all these friends.
こんなに 友達ができたよ｡
それが様変わりしたのは おそらく
芙蓉様の先が長くないことを➡
That probably changed when the doctor realized Fuyo-sama would not live much longer.
博士が察したからなのでしょう｡
He continued his reckless experiments in order to give Fuyo-san eternal life...
芙蓉様に永遠の命を と
ﾑﾁｬな実験を続け➡
あのような結果に…｡
((芙蓉…
私も からくりになりたいよ｡
Fuyo.
I want to become a robot, as well.
そうすれば こんな苦しみ
悲しみからも解放されるのに))
Then I will be released from this suffering and sadness.
(伍丸弐號)みんな 一緒だ｡
We're both the same now. If you're still lonely, then I will change this world.
それでも まだ寂しいというのなら
私が この世界を変えてやろう｡
(伍丸弐號)この国を…
からくりだけの国に変えてやろう｡
I will make this country...into a country of only robots.
((あぁ…
私は からくりになりたい))
Oh...I want to be a robot.
だから 戻ってこい…｡ 芙蓉！
So come back to me...
Fuyo!
娘のために 話し相手を
娘のために 永遠の命を➡
Someone his daughter could talk to;
eternal life for his daughter; living once more for his daughter's sake...
娘のために 再び命を｡
んで 今度は
兵隊 引き連れて 革命かい｡
And now bringing soldiers to him for a revolution, huh?
たいそうな親父さんだねぇ｡
(神楽)親父は 娘に弱いｱﾙ｡
That's some father she's got.
Fathers are suckers when it comes to their daughters.
You should know.
よく わかってんじゃねえか｡
My task was to serve the doctor and Fuyo-sama.
私の役目は
博士と芙蓉様のお役に立つこと｡
However, the seed that the doctor implanted in me did nothing.
でも 博士が私に組み込んだ種子は
何の反応もありません｡
私には あれは 博士とは思えない｡
あれは 博士の夢の残骸です｡
I do not think of that robot as the doctor.
That is just a mangled relic of his dream.
私には わかりません｡
Now that both the doctor and Fuyo-sama are gone, I do not know what I should do anymore.
博士も芙蓉様もいなくなった今
私が 何をなすべきか…｡
いるだろ｡
They're still there.
お前の大事な連中なら いるだろ｡
お前の中に｡
The people who are important to you are still there. Inside of you.
(芙蓉)種子のことですか｡
違えよ｡
Are you talking about "The Seed"?
That's not it.
んな 目に見えねえﾃﾞｰﾀだの
数字の羅列だの➡
It's not some data that you can't see, or a string of numbers,
ﾘｾｯﾄ押しながら 電源切らなきゃ
消えちまいそうなもんじゃねえ｡
or something that might disappear if you don't leave the power on when you push reset.
本当に大事な記憶ってなぁ➡
Truly important memories don't disappear no matter how many times
何回 電源切ろうが
ﾌﾞﾚｰｶｰ落ちようが とばねえよ｡
you flip the off switch or trip the circuit breaker.
あれ？
(神楽)何ｱﾙか？
Huh?
What happened?
(源外)ﾌﾞﾚｰｶｰ落ちたな
やっぱ 相当 電気くうみたいだ➡
The circuit breaker just tripped. Seems this robot draws quite a bit of juice.
この からくり｡
あれ？ なんか煙出てない？
Huh? Is that smoke?
いかん 容量が でかすぎたか｡
やっぱ➡
Uh-oh, it was too much. The kludge couldn't hold up, after all.
ありあわせの からくりじゃ
もたんかったぜ｡
おいおい また 記憶
とんじまったんじゃねえのか？
Hey, did her memory disappear again?
大丈夫ｱﾙ
ﾎﾝﾄに大事な記憶ってなぁ➡
Don't worry.
Truly important memories don't disappear even if there's smoke or if the circuit breaker trips.
ﾌﾞﾚｰｶｰ落ちようが 煙出ようが
消えねえｱﾙぜ｡
腹立つんだけど
この子 殴っていい？
You're pissing me off. Can I hit this girl?
そのへんの からくりで
代わりになるのは ねえのか｡
Don't you have a robot around that can take her place?
暗くて見えねえよ｡
穴探せ 穴｡
It's too dark to see.
Find the hole. The hole.
うっ｡
簡単に言いやがるぜ｡
You make it sound so simple. If only we had a similar robot maid.
せめて 同じ からくり家政婦でも
ありゃあな｡
(定春)ﾜﾝ｡
(ﾒｲﾄﾞ)お掃除ですの お掃除ですの｡
Clean up. Clean up.
(源外)でかした ﾎﾟﾁ！
これなら…｡
Good boy, Pochi! With this, I can...
(神楽)ﾎﾟﾁじゃない 定春ｱﾙ！
He's not Pochi. He's Sadaharu!
Oh, it's bright here thanks to the moonlight.
おぉ こっちは
月明かりで明るいな｡
あれ？ 月明かり…？
Huh? Moonlight?
月明かりしかねえ｡
There's only...moonlight.
町中 真っ暗ｱﾙ｡
The entire city is pitch dark.
野郎！
どういうこった こいつは…｡
The bastard! What's going on?!
江戸市民に告ぐ もうじき
この街は からくりに制圧される｡
To the citizens of Edo. The city will soon be taken over by a robot.
["What the?! A new form of terrorism?!"]
からくりが
人に支配される時代は 終わった｡
The age when robots are controlled by humans has come to an end.
我らが女王の御霊
帰還せしとき➡
When our queen's spirit returns,
からくりは 人に…
いや 神に等しき存在となる｡
a robot will become equal to humans... No, equal to God.
この御霊 戻らぬことあらば➡
If her spirit does not return, the blood of a sacrifice will be spilt.
生け贄の血が
流るることになろうぞ｡
(神楽)新八！
Shinpachi!
こいつは 名指しで
ｹﾝｶ売られたようなもんだな｡
It's like he's specifically calling us out to fight.
(神楽)上等ｱﾙ ﾐﾀﾏだか
ｷﾝﾀﾏだか知らないけど➡
Fine. Spirit, testicles, whatever! I'll deliver it to you!
届けにいってやるね｡
(芙蓉)ﾐﾀﾏでも
ｷﾝﾀﾏでもありません｡
I am neither a spirit, nor testicles.
卵です｡
I am Tama.
ありましたよ｡
It's here...
(芙蓉)はるか昔
私が目覚めたときの記憶｡
A memory from very long ago, when I first came to life.
油まみれの顔で
博士は私に こう言いました｡
With his face covered in oil the doctor said to me:
娘に笑顔を と…｡
"Make my daughter smile."
(芙蓉)どれだけ機能を拡張し
姿を変えようとも 忘れません｡
No matter how much I changed in capabilities or appearance,
I will never forget that.
今の博士を見て 芙蓉様は
笑ってくれると思いますか？
Do you think Fuyo-sama would smile if she saw what the doctor is now?
行くか その笑顔ってやつを
取り戻しに｡
Shall we go? To bring back that smile...?
Signs of life detected.
(ﾒｲﾄﾞ)生体反応 察知｡
この家屋に隠れている者は➡
The people hiding inside this house are to come out immediately and obey our orders.
速やかに出てきて
我々の指示に従いなさい｡
(ﾒｲﾄﾞ)警告します｡
この家屋に隠れている者は➡
Warning. The people inside this house...
速やかに出てきて
我々の指示に従い…｡
are to come out immediately and obey our orders...
(爆発音)
(源外)ｶﾞｰﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
見たか流山！ ｵﾒｴんとこの
華奢な からくりなんぞ➡
See that, Ryuzan?!
Your frail robots will be crushed by a single blow from my machines!
ﾜｼの からくりにかかりゃ
一撃粉砕よ｡
鎧 大砲 ｷｬﾀﾋﾟﾗ｡
Armor! Cannons! Caterpillar tracks! This is a man's machine!
(源外)これが
男の からくりじゃ！
じじい！ 男の からくりは
結構だが➡
Old man! It's great that you've got a man's machine,
もうちょっと ﾃﾞﾘｹｰﾄな運転
できねえのか！
but can you drive with a bit more control?!
銀の字 交通ﾙｰﾙ守って
命守れなかったじゃ 世話ねえや｡
Gin-no-ji! We can't save lives by obeying the traffic rules.
(源外)それにな からくりの扱いは
ｹﾝｶと同じよ｡
And besides, you handle machines like you handle a fight.
なめられたら しめえだ！
If you underestimate them, you're dead!
うおぉ～ 山ほど来やがった！
There's a mountain of them!
ｶﾞﾊﾊ！ かかってきやがれ
一網打尽にしてくれるわ｡
Come get us! I'll take you all down at once!
(ﾒｲﾄﾞたち)ｷｬｰｯ！
(源外)ｶﾞｰﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
銀ちゃん 後ろからも！
Gin-chan! Behind us!
神楽 傘の柄を引け！
Kagura! Pull on the umbrella handle!
(ﾒｲﾄﾞたち)ｷｬｰｯ!!
(源外)少々
いじくらせてもらったぞ｡
I took the liberty of modifying it. A peashooter's a bit outdated.
豆鉄砲なんざ 今どき古いわ｡
じじい でかしたｱﾙ！
これさえあれば…｡
Old man, nice job! With this, I...
After one shot, it needs to be recharged,
１回撃つと充電がいるが
醤油さしに 早変わりだ｡
but it turns immediately into a soy sauce dispenser.
(２人)だから なんで醤油!?
Why soy sauce?!
(ﾒｲﾄﾞたち)たぁ～！
銀の字 木刀の柄を押せ！
Gin-no-ji! Push on your wooden sword's grip!
とりゃあ～!!
(ﾒｲﾄﾞたち)たぁ～！
It dispenses soy sauce.
醤油が出る｡
だから なんで醤油だ！
So, why soy sauce?! This is just a stick that dispenses soy sauce!
お前 これ
ただの醤油出る棒だろうが！
(源外)時間がなかったんだ｡
I didn't have enough time. Be grateful I at least modified it.
改造してやっただけでも
ありがたく思え この｡
I'm not grateful. This is like a kid's prank!
ありがたくねえよ わんぱく坊主の
いたずらﾚﾍﾞﾙだよ これ｡
(源外)あれだぞ
卵かけご飯 混ぜながら➡
It's an item that lets you stir your raw egg on rice while adding soy sauce.
醤油を加味していける代物だ｡
(神楽)ﾏｼﾞｱﾙか！
納豆ご飯もいけるｱﾙ｡
Seriously? It'd be great with natto on rice, too!
[Note: Natto is fermented soybeans.]
お前らは
醤油を１本 丸飲みしろ！
You two should drink a whole bottle of soy sauce!
あら ｽｶｲﾊｲ！
Oh, Sky High?!
じいさん こいつは…！
(源外)鬼ヶ島につながる道よ｡
Old man, what's that?
The path to Onigashima!
野郎は おそらく
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙの地下深くにいる｡
He's probably deep beneath the Terminal.
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙ…｡
Terminal?
[Next episode: "Some Data Cannot Be Erased."]
[No. To-502 is the leader of the coup d'etat. Dr. Hayashi's character data is implanted in its body.]
[The robot army has taken over the Terminal. Can Gintoki and his friends defeat them?!]